[{"question":" From what distribution does the `rand()` function return value?","options":[{"text":"normal","correct":false},{"text":"poisson","correct":false},{"text":"binomial","correct":false},{"text":"uniform","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Based on the code below, c is the `\\_` of a.","options":[{"text":"median","correct":true},{"text":"mode","correct":false},{"text":"mean","correct":false},{"text":"margin","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\na = rand(1, 11);\nb = sort(a);\nc = b(1, ceil(end/2));\n```"},{"question":" What does the Profiler track?","options":[{"text":"execution time","correct":true},{"text":"command history","correct":false},{"text":"errors","correct":false},{"text":"the value of variables","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which code block contains the correct syntax for a `while` loop?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\na = 0;\nwhile a < 5\n    a = a + 1;\nend\n```"},{"question":" What does `b` contain?","options":[{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nb =\n     8    19\n    19    46\n```"},{"question":" You have written a function `myfun` and want to measure how long it takes to run. Which code segment will return in `t` the time in seconds it takes `myfun` to run?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nt = timer(myfun());\n```"},{"question":" What is `%%` used for?","options":[{"text":"argument placeholder","correct":false},{"text":"block quotes","correct":false},{"text":"code sections","correct":true},{"text":"conversion specifier","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" what is the `.` character NOT used for?","options":[{"text":"structure field access","correct":false},{"text":"a decimal point","correct":false},{"text":"cell array access","correct":true},{"text":"element-wise operations","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Which function could you use for multiple linear regression?","options":[{"text":"polyval","correct":false},{"text":"regress","correct":true},{"text":"solve","correct":false},{"text":"polyfit","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". For which of these arrays do `mean`, `median`, and `mode` return the same value?","options":[{"text":"[0 1 1 1 2]","correct":true},{"text":"[1 3 5 5 6]","correct":false},{"text":"[0 1 1 1 1]","correct":false},{"text":"[0 0 5 5 5]","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You are in the middle of a long MATLAB session where you have performed many analyses and made many plots. You run the following commands, yet a figure window doesn't pop up on the top of your screen with your plot. What might be the issue?","options":[{"text":"Your plot doesn't plot in a figure window because `figure` was not called immediately in advance.","correct":false},{"text":"Your `plot` syntax is incorrect.","correct":false},{"text":"Your plot is in a figure window that was already open, hidden behind other windows on your screen.","correct":true},{"text":"Your plot was saved to an image file but not displayed.","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nx = [-1:0.1:1];\ny = X.^2;\nplot(x, y)\n```"},{"question":". How do you access the value for the field `name` in structure S?","options":[{"text":"S['name']","correct":false},{"text":"S.name","correct":true},{"text":"S('name')","correct":false},{"text":"S{'name'}","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What built-in definition does i have?","options":[{"text":"basic imaginary unit","correct":true},{"text":"index function","correct":false},{"text":"infinity","correct":false},{"text":"index variable","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement is equivalent to this for loop?","options":[{"text":"b = a\\*a;","correct":false},{"text":"b = a.^2;","correct":true},{"text":"b = a^2;","correct":false},{"text":"b = pow2(a);","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\na = [1 2 3; 4 5 6];\nb = zeros(size(a));\nfor i_row = 1:size(a, 1)\n    for i_col = 1:size(a, 2)\n        b(i_row, i_col) = a(i_row, i_col)^2;\n    end\nend\n```"},{"question":". You have plotted values of cosine from -10 to 10 and want to change the x-axis tick marks to every pi, from -3*pi to 3*pi. Which statement will do that?","options":[{"text":"xticks(-3*pi:3.14:3*pi)","correct":false},{"text":"xticks(-3*pi:pi:3*pi)","correct":true},{"text":"xticks(linespace(-3*pi(), 3*pi(), pi()))","correct":false},{"text":"xticks(linespace(-3*pi, 3*pi, pi)","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the value of `c`?","options":[{"text":"[-1 2 -1]","correct":false},{"text":"[1 3 6 5 3]","correct":true},{"text":"6","correct":false},{"text":"[1 -2 1]","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\na = ones(1,3);\nb = 1:3;\nc = conv(a,b)\n```"},{"question":". Which function CANNOT be used to randomly sample data?","options":[{"text":"datasample","correct":false},{"text":"randi","correct":false},{"text":"resample","correct":true},{"text":"randperm","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which choice is correct syntax for a `switch` statement?","options":[{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nx = 7;\nswitch x\n    case 2\n        disp(\"two\");\n    default\n        disp(\"not two\");\nend\n```"},{"question":". What is the result of this code?","options":[{"text":"Error","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nc =\n    -0.2500\n```"},{"question":". What is true of a handle class object?","options":[{"text":"When you pass a handle object to a function, a new object is made that is independent of the original.","correct":false},{"text":"All copies of handle objects refer to the same underlying object.","correct":true},{"text":"Handle object cannot reference one another.","correct":false},{"text":"Handle object do not have a default `eq` function.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which choice has a different final result in `f10` than the other three?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```MATLAB\nf10 = 1;\ni = 1;\nwhile i <= 10\n    i   = i + 1;\n    f10 = i * f10;\nend\n```"},{"question":". Which choice will NOT give you a 5 x 5 identity matrix?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\na = rand(5);\nround(a * inv(a))\n```"},{"question":". Which statement creates this structure?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\ndog('name')   = 'Bindy';\ndog('breed')  = 'border collie';\ndog('weight') = 32;\n```"},{"question":". `my_func` is a function as follows. What is the value of `a` at the end of the code beneath?","options":[{"text":"4","correct":false},{"text":"3","correct":false},{"text":"0","correct":false},{"text":"1","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\nfunction a = my_func(a)\n    a = a + 1;\nend\n------------------\na = 0;\nfor i = 1:3\n    my_func(a);\nend\na = my_func(a);\n```"},{"question":". Which statement could create this cell array?","options":[{"text":"c = {\"hello world\" {\"hello\"} \"goodbye\" [1 2 ]};","correct":false},{"text":"c = {\"hello world\" {\"hello\"} \"goodbye\" {[1 2 3]}};","correct":false},{"text":"c = {\"hello world\" {\"hello\"} \"goodbye\" [1 2 3]};","correct":true},{"text":"c = {\"hello world\" {\"hello\" \"hello\"} \"goodbye\" {[1 2 3]}};","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nc =\n    {[\"hello world\"]}    {1×1 cell}    {[\"goodbye\"]}    {1×3 double}\n```"},{"question":". Which choice adds `b` to each row of `a`?","options":[{"text":"a = a + reshape(b, 4, 1);","correct":false},{"text":"a = a + b';","correct":false},{"text":"a = a + repmat(b, 4, 1);","correct":true},{"text":"a = a + [b b b b];","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\na = ones(4, 4);\nb= [1 2 3 4];\n```"},{"question":". Which choice replaces all `a`s with `o`s?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nfor i = 1:length(fruit)\n    fruit{i}(fruit{i} == 'a') == 'o';\n```"},{"question":". Which statement returns the roots for the polynomial `x^2 + 2x - 4`?","options":[{"text":"poly([1 2 -4])","correct":false},{"text":"solve(x^2 + 2x - 4 == 0)","correct":false},{"text":"polyfit(x^2 + 2x - 4 == 0)","correct":false},{"text":"roots([1 2 -4])","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which choice is the proper syntax to append a new elements `a` to the end of 1x 2 dimensional cell array `C`?","options":[{"text":"C = {C a};","correct":false},{"text":"C = cellcat(C a)","correct":false},{"text":"C = cat(2, {a}, C)","correct":false},{"text":"C{end+1}=a","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You have loaded a dataset of people's heights into a 100 x 1 array called `height`. Which statement will return a 100 x 1 array, `sim_height`, with values from a normal distribution with the same mean and variance as your height data?","options":[{"text":"sim_height = std(height) + mean(height) \\* randn(100, 1);","correct":false},{"text":"sim_height = mean(height) + std(height) \\* randn(100, 1);","correct":true},{"text":"sim_height = randn(std(height), mean(height), [100, 1]);","correct":false},{"text":"sim_height = randn(mean(height), std(height), [100, 1]);","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement returns a cell array of the strings containing '`burger`' from `menu`?","options":[{"text":"menu{strfind(menu, 'burger')}","correct":false},{"text":"menu(strfind(menu, 'burger'))","correct":false},{"text":"menu{contains(menu, 'burger')}","correct":false},{"text":"menu(contains(menu, 'burger'))","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the set of possible values that `a` may contain?","options":[{"text":"3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12","correct":false},{"text":"1, 2, 12","correct":true},{"text":"2, 11, 12","correct":false},{"text":"1, 12","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\na      = randi(10, [1, 10]);\na(3)   = 11;\na(a>2) = 12;\n```"},{"question":". Which statement is true about the sparse matrices?","options":[{"text":"You can use the `sparse` function to remove empty cells from cell array variables.","correct":false},{"text":"Sparse matrices always use less memory than their associated full matrices.","correct":true},{"text":"Mixtures of sparse and full matrices can be combined in all of MATLAB's built-in arithmetic operations.","correct":false},{"text":"The `sparse` function requires its input to be a full matrix with at least 50% zero elements.","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement using logical indices will result in an error?","options":[{"text":"b = a(a ~= 11)","correct":false},{"text":"b = a(a == 1)","correct":false},{"text":"b = a(a>6 && a<9)","correct":true},{"text":"b = a(a | 1)","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which statement turns `menu` into the variable `menu_string` below?","options":[{"text":"menu_string = cell2mat(join(menu, newline))","correct":true},{"text":"menu_string = cell2mat(join(menu, '\\n'))","correct":false},{"text":"menu_string = join(menu, newline)","correct":false},{"text":"menu_string = cell2mat(pad(menu))","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nmenu = {'hot dog' 'corn dog' 'regular burger' 'cheeseburger' 'veggie burger'}\nmenu_string =\n    'hot dog\n     corn dog\n     regular burger\n     cheeseburger\n     veggie burger'\n```"},{"question":". Which code snippet sets a new random seed based on the current time and saves the current settings of the random number generator?","options":[{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nrng('shuffle');\nrng_settings_curr = rng();\n```"},{"question":". You have a matrix `data` in which each column is mono audio recording from a room in your house. You've noticed that each column has a very different mean and when you plot them all on the same graph, the spread across the y axis make it impossible to see anything. You want to subtract the mean from each column. Which code block will accomplish this?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\ndata_nomean = zeros(size(data));\nfor i = 1:size(data, 1)\n    data_nomean(i, :) = data(i, :) - mean(data(i, :));\nend\n```"},{"question":". Which code block results in an array `b` containing the mean values of each array within `C`?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\nb = zeros(1, size(C, 1));\nfor i_C = 1:size(C, 1)\n    b(i_C) = mean(C{i_C}(:));\nend\n```"},{"question":". Which statement creates a logical array that is 1 if the element in `passwords` contains a digit and 0 if it does not?","options":[{"text":"contains(password, '\\d')","correct":false},{"text":"~isempty(regexp(passwords, '\\d'))","correct":false},{"text":"cellfun(@(x) ~isempty(regexp(x, '\\d')), passwords)","correct":true},{"text":"regexp(passwords, '\\d')","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which is NOT a function that adds text to a plot?","options":[{"text":"title","correct":false},{"text":"text","correct":false},{"text":"label","correct":true},{"text":"legend","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which code block most likely produced this graph?","options":[{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":true}],"illustrator":"```\nfigure\nx = rand(10,10);\nr = corrcoef(x);\nimagesc(r)\ncolorbar\n```"},{"question":". What kind of files are stored with the .mat extension?","options":[{"text":"figure files","correct":false},{"text":"script files","correct":false},{"text":"function files","correct":false},{"text":"stored variable files","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You would like to randomly reorder every element in array a and put the result into another array b. Which code is NOT necessary to do that?","options":[{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nb = a(randperm(10));\n```"},{"question":". Which statement returns **1** (true)?","options":[{"text":"a == b","correct":true},{"text":"ischar(b)","correct":false},{"text":"length(a) == length(b)","correct":false},{"text":"class(a) == class(b)","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\na = 'stand'\nb = \"stand\"\n```"},{"question":". Which does E contain?","options":[{"text":"E = {'cat'} {'dog'}","correct":true},{"text":"E = {'mouse'}","correct":false},{"text":"E = {'cat'} {'cow'} {'dog'} {'piranha'}","correct":false},{"text":"E =","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\nC = {'dog' 'cat' 'mouse'}\nD = {'cow' 'piranha' 'mouse'}\nE = setdiff(C,D)\n```"},{"question":". Where in the UI can you see what variables have been created, their values, and their class?","options":[{"text":"Editor","correct":false},{"text":"command window","correct":false},{"text":"details","correct":false},{"text":"workspace","correct":true}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Given the following x and y coordinates, which choice calculates a linear regression for the x and y coordinates, and which plots the points of the x,y data and the regression line on the same graph?","options":[{"text":"","correct":true},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false},{"text":"","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\ncoeff_line = polyfit(x,y,1);\nx_line = floor(min(x)):0.1:ceil(max(x));\ny_line = polyval(coeff_line,x_line);\nfigure; plot(x,y,'o')\nhold on\nplot(x_line,y_line)\n```"},{"question":". If you run this piece of code, you will get an error. Why?","options":[{"text":"You are attempting to multiply a non-square matrix by itself, causing a dimension mismatch.","correct":true},{"text":"MATLAB does not allow you to square all the elements in the matrix in a single operation.","correct":false},{"text":"You must use the \\*\\* operator instead of the ^ operator.","correct":false},{"text":"You cannot square matrices that have a 0 as the first element.","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\na = [0 1 2 3; 4 5 6 7];\na = a^2;\n```"}]